Podcasting 2.0 from May 30th,
2025, episode 222, Pod Pollution.
Hello, everybody.
We are back after a one-week absence,
and boy, does it feel good to be back.
The place that you tune into to find
out what's happening in the future of
podcasting, some of what's
going on now, and of course,
we always like to look back into the past.
We are the only boardroom
that wasn't invited
to the secret Purple Apple London meeting.
I'm Adam Curry, here in the heart of
the Texas Hill Country, and in Alabama,
the man who was walking aimlessly
in the woods just last week.
Say hello to my friend on the other
end, the one, the only, Mr. Dave Jones.
The forest.
The forest. Oh, it was the forest?
Yes.
It wasn't the woods, it was the forest?
I was in the forest.
But see, walking in the forest sounds
not as good as walking in the woods.
Walking in the woods with the one.
The alliteration.
Yes, well, you know, that's what disc
jockeys are all about, man. Alliteration.
Yeah, that was, it was great.
It was great to be in nature.
Yeah, so what'd you do? You went out
with your son? You went hiking around?
Very nice.
We did a, it was going to be
three days, we did two days,
it was like a 20 mile loop.
Where, what woods? What
woods? The woods of Alabama?
Talladega National Forest.
Known from Talladega Nights?
It's near Talladega, yes, Talladega 500.
Yeah, very nice.
It's a national forest.
It is home of the highest point,
the highest point in Alabama,
which is Mount Cheeha.
Yeah, that's 24...
Sounds like an Alabama.
Mount Cheeha!
Mount Cheeha, everybody!
Yeah, yeah, Mount Cheeha.
Let's see, how tall is Mount Cheeha?
It's, I mean, by our, you know,
by other standards, it's modest,
but for us it's, yeah, 2,400 feet.
That's, that's, that's mild.
That's very...
In Texas, that's practically, you know...
Well, we're in the hill country, we
are at 1,200 feet where we live.
Oh, really?
It's hill country.
I mean, it's not that you get much higher
than 2,000 or 2,500 feet, but yeah.
What is the highest elevation in Texas?
I'm, let's see.
Oh, you got me.
You got me on that.
It might be, what is that
mountain we got near?
The highest elevation in
Texas is at Guadalupe Peak.
And what's the elevation of that?
Located within Guadalupe
Mountains National Park.
It stands at 8,751 feet.
Holy crap.
That's tall.
That's, that's almost oxygen level.
You can need a tank.
Yeah.
Yeah, we have...
You gotta get a Sherpa to get up there.
We have, we have Sacred
Rock, what's it called here?
Sacred Rock, Mellow Rock, Hard Rock, some
rock, some rock, some rock out here.
But that's nowhere near 8,000 feet.
I like AI.
I like AI says, the
peak can be, Guadalupe,
the peak can be climbed
by a maintained strenuous
day hike via the Guadalupe, what is that?
What kind of language is this?
Guadalupe.
Maintained strenuous day hike.
Well, it's an LLM.
What do you expect?
You expect it to speak English?
Oh, don't be so crazy.
But I will say this week in
Vibe Coding, I figured it out.
I know how to do it.
It's really cool.
I'm, I'm, I'm digging it.
What, I mean, what?
Breakthrough.
What was your latest breakthrough?
Well, just, just now I understand that you
have to continuously watch this idiocy.
The number of times I've, you know,
I'm setting up doing a setup script.
So I take two other
scripts, templatize it.
And I swear to God, for no reason,
the AI will change the user agent
from Godcaster app 1.0 to Mozilla.
Mozilla.
Why?
Why Mozilla?
That's an interesting choice.
It always does this.
You know, I'm seeing all these 403 errors.
I'm like, what's going on now?
Oh, it doesn't matter how many
times, you know, Grok has this, uh,
workspace, workspace.
All, it will understand things from
all conversations in the workspace.
Yeah.
I don't think so.
I've told it a million times.
This is the user agent.
Do not, do not, all caps,
do not always use this.
And lo and behold, it
changes it just willy nilly.
I've never, I've never done vibe coding.
I mean, I've used some AI, some LLM
stuff to, to generate some code,
but I don't think I've done the
vibe coding thing where you're just
kind of like telling it what to do over
and over and like getting output from it.
That's pretty much what I do.
So I'm, I'm, I'm just wondering what this,
I'm a little unsure of
how your process works
because like when you, do
you feed, so do you get a,
a script and then want it to add
something, want to add something to it?
And do you feed back its own script to
it and just tell it to modify that?
Uh, no.
So it remembers the script it gave you.
And then it's pretty good at
creating lots of logging.
So it'll say, show me
this, show me these logs.
And, you know, but it
inevitably, it's not,
it's not asking for the
stuff that really breaks.
You know, it's like, no, no, I can
see clearly what's going wrong.
And once you go down a path,
you've got to catch it.
This is when you have to say, stop,
here's the script that was working.
We're starting over.
You have to stop it or it will take you
all the way down to a kernel rebuild.
I mean, it's just, it is so stupid.
I mean, and so I, I know
what I wanted to do.
I have limited, limited knowledge of
coding, but I could, I understand,
you know, and I understand
the difference between, okay.
So for no reason you put a single
quote instead of a double quote.
So, and that's why there's an error.
Hello.
Um, that happens very frequently.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Typo on my, you're a computer.
How can you make this typo?
That makes no sense.
That's the one thing you
should be able to do.
I'm sorry for that.
I misspelled that word.
Also, you know, it'll do like,
this is all Python scripts.
It'll, it'll comment stuff out with,
uh, with quadruple, uh, quote marks.
And, you know, it's just
like, stop, just don't do it.
What's wrong with, I don't know Python well
enough to know what is wrong with that.
Yeah, me neither, but me neither,
but I know that it doesn't work.
Okay.
I've learned a lot more.
So the one thing that was just really
interesting, I have these two scripts,
they work in one instance.
I'll say, okay.
And I could say to it,
replace this number with this number
and this number with this number
and give me new scripts.
Works perfectly.
Okay.
You know, so literally like player number
33, I want you to change that to 18.
Telnet port 38, uh, 33 changes to 3,018.
Okay.
Does it perfectly works.
So now I want to templatize this.
So I just have one script.
I give you a number.
You create these two scripts with these
numbers and it's derived from this.
It's, it's simple, right?
Well, no.
Sounds to me.
Oh, and it just went down this path
because it, it tried to templatize it.
And then it was doing, oh no, I'm sorry.
We have to have a double dollar signs
instead of single dollar signs.
And after two hours, I
said, you know what?
Put these two scripts into a script
and just do a search and replace.
Boom.
Script works immediately.
So you could have done that yourself.
Pretty much.
With a text editor.
Grep.
I said, yeah, so, uh, but it's
been, it's been incredible.
It's very rewarding.
Once you understand how
to use these things,
which is always looking because it's dumb.
I, you know, if you don't know,
if you don't know what you want,
you're going to be a master vibe coder.
Honestly, a master, you're going to be,
you're going to be really good at, um,
like knowing where the, you're
going to be a prompt jockey.
That's what you're going to be in a way.
Well, Bemro says vibe
coding is the easy part.
Vibe debugging is where they're,
yeah, that's exactly right.
Yeah, that's true.
Because, I mean, I can see that, you know,
I just understand the
basics of, of coding.
So I see the things that are going wrong,
but when, if you don't catch it, man,
then you go down a path, a never ending
path that's happened to me so many times.
Now I know, stop.
No, we're not going to do that.
I'll even start a new conversation.
So that's, that's what I was really
confused about is when you start, okay,
let you, you have a, uh, you have a VC
session, a vibe coding session today.
Yeah.
And then tomorrow you want
to start a new VC session.
How do you start that?
Because I'm assuming it think it's
forgotten what all you did the day before.
Well, no, cause you have to, you can
pick up, so you have the workspace.
This I'm using Grok.
That's the only one I've been
able to get to work and, and,
and it seems to like Python.
So that's fine.
Um, so you have a conversation at a certain
point, the conversation is so long.
You can see it start to slow down cause
it's all running in a browser and that,
you know, and then it'll,
instead of printing the code in
the handy little code box to the right, it
prints it out in your conversation
on formatted and you're like, stop,
you're doing it wrong.
It's starting to lose itself.
It's starting to lose.
So then I'll take the code that works,
put it into a new conversation and,
and because it's well documented, it
documents its own code pretty well.
So it, so it can read what it's
doing, but believe me, the,
the idea that it remembers
stuff from other conversations.
No, this is where, right.
You start a new conversation.
Oh, I think I'll turn this user agent
to Mozilla because that's just better.
That's just better.
You just need that.
Do you have a prompt that you start
with that says some like that you've,
um, accrued over time?
Something that says like,
uh, here's a script.
Here's the script that I'm working on.
Do not change the user agent to Mozilla.
Yeah.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Do you have like a bullet point list of all
the things you're telling it not to do?
Yeah.
Two or three of those things.
What's really bad is when you find
yourself yelling in all caps,
like you did this wrong again.
That's when you got to go take a walk.
It's like, and it'll
say, oh, I'm, I'm sorry.
You're so disappointed.
No, I can't have this
conversation with you.
Anyway, anyway.
Um, so, uh, yeah, so we went to Nashville.
Uh, we saw basically four mini
concerts and then we're a part of a,
an award show, not in the award
show, but part of the award show.
It's always kind of surreal
when you have the podcast
of the year award and I'm just sitting
there in the audience like,
holy cow, man, isn't that cool?
Isn't that just cool that there's awards
now for, for podcasts and, you know,
on a, on a, in the grand old Opry, you
know, it just felt kind of crazy, isn't it?
And, uh, so when we got back,
what was this connected to?
Oh, so Caleb is, uh, Caleb,
Caleb is pretty much,
they've bought up every single Christian
music radio station,
500, over 500 of them.
They bought them all, all of them.
And they, and they've
homogenized it into one station.
So they have one morning show.
They've got one, you know,
they've got personalities,
but it's the same across
the entire country.
Um, and it's a very tight playlist.
So all these artists, they're
pretty much tied into Caleb.
In fact, the, the Christian
music labels are going
out of business because they don't need
representation anywhere else.
There's no other stations to promote.
Wow.
And so I've been talking to
several of these artists,
the main one being Matthew West, who
he's probably written 25%
of the songs these days.
Cause he, you know, because
they're a nonprofit, they pay a,
a infinitesimal amount of
performing rights royalties.
Okay.
So, so you have your song, this
station makes $300 million a year.
They just built a $100 million
building in Nashville.
It's Franklin, I think, um, with
sound stages and everything.
So you're Matthew West, you're
writing all this stuff.
It's only getting played
on one super station.
You get almost no money for it.
And now you're walking into
the $100 million building
to do your dance for the people that
are basically becoming very well
wealthy off of, off of your music.
And so I've been talking
to several people and
there is some interest
for value for value.
There is some real interest.
Now, interest translating to, yeah,
okay, I'll do it is a big step.
As we, as we have learned.
Yes.
But you know, I'm, I'm pushing,
I'm putting the feelers out.
They're definitely like, wait a minute.
So you had a, you had these bands at
Antones and Austin and they made five,
600 bucks each just from
performing on an internet thing.
So yeah, pretty much.
Oh, okay.
So then they get interested,
but they're all,
I think Nashville's
like anywhere else, you
know, that they're so like, well,
just in case I make it big,
I'm going to do the, do
it half, half, you know, don't
really want to do it all the way.
And the system, the system is really
super rigged against everybody, man.
If you sit down with, um, um, he's
like Costello's mom for, Oh, she'll,
she'll talk your ear off
about how, uh, about how, uh, just
about how useless Nashville is now.
And I mean, you go there
and you end up playing, um,
you go there and you end up
playing in those bars and
stuff along, along main street.
Yeah.
Oh, that's the worst.
There's like a list of songs
that they, they, they're like,
you're going to play these 25 songs.
Not just that four hours, no breaks.
Uh-huh.
And you're not even allowed
to play your own material.
And so you can't, you never get discovered
because you're not playing anything.
That's not on the list.
So this all happened in the Gaylord
hotel, which is basically the biodome,
you know, it's like a Truman show.
And so there's this one bar and you
know, like in the afternoon we go there,
we sit and have
a drink and there'd always be a different
Nashville musician performing there.
And, and I get talking with
one, with a one young lady.
He's like, Oh, this is really the
best gig because I get breaks.
What?
Yeah.
It was five hours, but I get to go to
the bathroom at least once an hour.
Like, wow.
And she was so Dave, she was so good.
She, she just, it was phenomenal.
Her, the way she sounded, she, you
know, played guitar of course.
And, and, you know, our church
is looking for a worship leader.
And so I'm there with the pastors
and they say, Hey, you know,
we have a job opening and
this job is like $65,000 a year.
It's not a, not a crap job.
Yeah.
And so, you know, they're talking
to her and she's not married.
She's young.
She could move whenever she wants, but
nah, nah, I'm going to stay in Nashville.
Cause you know, my, my day is coming.
My break is coming.
No, it's not.
I'm sorry.
No, no, no, no.
Every, every that's, that's the
old thing is like, uh, you know,
as good as you think
you are, every, you know, every janitor
is a better guitar player than you are.
It's like you go to LA
and your Uber driver has
had two callbacks for CSI and he's on the
verge of breaking through.
Oh, sure.
Yeah.
Right.
Almost.
I got, I got two callbacks already.
I'm going to be a star and he
looks hot, you know, like, Oh wow.
Yeah.
I'm, uh, our local Christian
music station is WDJC.
I was looking up to see if they were
owned by K love when they, when they,
when they buy
a station, do they just rebrand it and
it just becomes K love low, you know?
Uh, well the call letters
have to stay the same,
but it just becomes a K love station.
There are a, obviously still a few
local music stations, but not many.
And, you know, I see, I don't think
this one is a K love station.
I think it's still, it looks independent.
It's got a big staff.
But, you know, um, so these big networks,
another big one, Salem radio, no Moody.
I'm sorry.
They just basically killed 60
plus morning shows in one swoop.
Yeah.
That was, that was really unexpected.
Not to me.
I mean, like they came out of the blue.
They didn't give anybody, you know,
the people who were doing the
morning shows didn't expect it.
Yeah.
It's like they showed up.
It's like that old thing of you, you showed
up and the doors are locked, you know?
Yeah, exactly.
And, um, and so, and,
uh, by chance, I guess,
is there any such thing as coincidence?
Uh, my talk with John Fuller from Focus
on the Family from NRB went out on, uh,
they put it out on a YouTube video.
And the, and the title was that
is the future of radio is local.
And we're talking about all the
stuff we're doing, lit, on demand,
value for value, all of this stuff.
And you got people posting
like, oh, that's interesting.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know, cause of course
all this stuff that
we're doing translates hyperlocal, man.
That's what I've been saying.
Hyperlocal podcasts for your community.
Do it live, have it on demand.
All this stuff is coming to bear.
It'll take another years, you know, a
couple of years, but it's happening.
It is happening.
I can see the future.
Um, where, we'll see.
Where is that talk to local?
I don't know.
You said it's on YouTube?
Yeah.
I posted it on podcastindex.social.
No one commented, of course.
I missed it.
Yeah, exactly.
Everyone hates me.
I got to comment, comment
on Curry's, Curry's thing.
Anyway, um, yeah.
So, came back, and then I was onboarded,
uh, to the new, um, Fountain,
Fountain Blue system.
Yeah, tell me about that.
Uh, so, and I'm, I'm a paying
customer, just so you know.
First of all, I just, I learned that
$50 a month gets you two shows.
Okay.
That makes a lot of sense.
Um, so besides the fact
that you can do a lot
of stuff that I'm not going to do, like
video, very interesting.
They're offering video hosting.
To see how that works, yes.
Um, you know, the L402, I think.
Is it 401 or 402?
Yeah.
L402 stuff.
So, I just set it up.
So, we onboarded Curry and the
Keeper, because I said, you know,
I'll give this a shot with you guys.
Um, so first of all, the, the, the onboard,
they already had everything in there.
And I said, how did you
get my boost in there?
So, well, these are obviously only
the boost from Fountain, because,
and they're the boost-agrams,
um, because they have been
sending the metadata,
formerly known as TLV
records, over Nostar.
But you don't need a Nostar account.
They're just using the Nostar system.
And so, that was quite impressive,
that they had everything kind
of already pulled in there.
What, what's really cool about
this, you know, you know,
I don't care about how many people
downloaded, but they have
everything all in one place.
So, your boost-agrams,
your Fiat, uh, support,
and it's all in your hosting dashboard.
It just makes so much sense.
I'm like, oh, I can use this.
Now I get it.
You know, your top supporters,
uh, top supporters by episode.
That's just, you know, you're, so
they have an audience tab and,
and you can see, well,
obviously you have the typical, where
are people coming from and all that.
An activity tab, which, you
know, that's basically helipad.
And, and so we also set up, you know,
just a support thing so
that what's coming is the
open support, do whatever you want.
And so, you onboard into Stripe right in
their interface, which was impressive.
Um, I, because I'm like, oh man, is
this Stripe thing going to be easy?
Surprisingly easy.
You know, you just provide
your, um, you get an account.
I don't know what you mean.
So, you, you, you're saying
that you set up a wallet.
No, no.
Stripe with a P.
Okay.
So the credit card processing.
Oh, for, for Fiat payments.
Yeah.
For Fiat payments.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
So you do that right in the system.
And I thought, oh, this is
going to be a pain in the butt.
But it's, so I, I actually set
up my account on the plane,
on the plane ride back and like,
I'll kind of have to do this other stuff.
But then, uh, when I got
in, it's just like log in.
And then, you know, it asks you for,
uh, your routing number for your bank.
And I within like five or eight minutes
I was done and the thing was working.
And I didn't have to set up a
product and all this stuff that's,
that Stripe is asking
you for through their normal setup.
Um, so, you know, it
sets up a, uh, you know,
just sets it all up and just
set it up and it works.
And, um, and so they don't
have the open donation yet,
but now if you go to curry and
the keeper and the fountain app underneath,
um, uh, you know, when you go to the,
to the page, it says support this show.
And I just set it at $20 a
month just to see how it works.
And it works.
And, uh, uh, and so it's limited to
that amount, which is not in my mind,
value for value, but they
are going to change.
That's coming.
There's a ticket out there
for that, but yeah, I got it.
Um, and I don't even know if they're
doing that through the funding tag.
I would have to look at the feed and
understand how they're doing that.
Trying to look it up on, uh, uh,
Korean, the keeper in my, uh,
you can get the feed from the index.
We put a, we put a redirect on it.
So yeah.
Okay.
So that's the, the L four Oh two
spec that that's what did that.
So I could have said, here's a bonus
episode or here's something else,
but I just said, no,
you're just going to get a badge.
Here you go.
You got a badge.
Congratulations.
Here's your badge.
And play an episode.
I just want to see if it gives
you the funding familiar tunes.
So let me hit funding.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
So, Oh, Oh, okay.
So if I hit the funding, well,
if I hit the funding button
and cast a matic on the Korean
keeper podcast, it, it
takes me to a web view
and then that comes up
and it says, how much
do you want to, let's see,
boost, add your name.
Let's see.
Let's, let's do this.
Dave Jones.
Is it only boost or can
you do Fiat there as well?
Uh, it looks like you can do Fiat.
There's a pay with bank card option.
Oh yeah.
Oh.
Okay.
It said, uh, heads up Oscar.
Um, it didn't work.
No, no, no, no.
You have a text, uh, style, you have
a style issue in your input form.
It's coming through as dark
gray on a black background.
I can't read my name when I type my name.
Okay.
So test.
One second.
So if I, this is actually
something I didn't even realize.
I think the way they've done it, I
think this will be better with video.
Honestly, sorry, everybody.
Um, but I'm, I guess what
you're seeing here is
a perfect storm of hosting company and app
working together and,
and doing a good job.
So let me see on my podcast guru, which
is my, here, support this podcast.
Okay.
I just paid you $10 with
my, with my visa card.
Wow.
Do I have to take you out for dinner now?
Uh, if you want to be a,
uh, let me see monetize.
If you want to get this,
the top secret content.
Yes.
Let me see.
It hasn't come in yet.
So it's for, uh, episode one 34.
Uh, well, I just hit the funding tag.
Yeah.
And I don't know if it's
tied to an episode or not.
I don't know if it's an
episode level funding time.
That's a good point.
Let me see.
I mean, I sent $10 to somebody.
Somebody got it.
I'm assuming it's you.
I haven't seen it come in yet.
I don't know.
I mean, I expect my bonus episode.
Yeah.
No, you, you, you get nothing.
Okay.
You're not, you're not,
you're getting zero.
You're getting zero from me.
Okay.
It went through on the
credit card to curry.com
is how it shows up on the credit card.
Yeah.
That's, that's what I,
that's what I entered.
Yeah.
That's stripe.
Okay.
So it should show up here.
Monetization anytime soon.
We see quarters.
I don't see it.
That's kind of lame.
Hmm.
You expect to see it.
Maybe it went to Oscar.
Well, that's the top.
That's their monetization strategy.
Well done boys.
Good job.
I'm sure it came in somewhere.
I just, I'm not seeing it.
Hmm.
But I mean, it was an easy experience.
I mean, it worked.
It worked fine.
When it comes up, it says, um.
Yeah.
You can support with sats or you can
support with, uh, with the card.
Right.
Yeah.
You get two buttons, pay with
lightning or pay with bank card.
And then, you know, it's, it stripes
you if you do the bank, bank card.
It let me do, actually,
I did it with Apple pay.
Oh.
Because when you kick out the stripe.
Yeah.
You hit pay with bank card.
When you kick the stripe, it
gives you the Apple pay option.
So I just double clicked into the Apple.
Okay.
That's cool.
I took a screenshot of the,
uh, text color problem.
I'm going to send that to Oscar.
Okay.
Um, okay.
So I don't know.
I guess that should show up
somewhere, but I haven't seen it.
It'll, it'll show up eventually.
Well, I'll let you know if it does.
I hope it does.
Um, okay.
So, oh, so that's how they did this.
So they tie the, the funding tag.
They tie that to their page where
you can choose to use sats or fiat.
The beauty of this is
from what I understand
is every app can integrate because all the
information is in the feed and
the boostogram information
comes through their Nostra setup.
So I guess they're probably hosting,
uh, a relay is what I'm guessing.
Yes.
They have their own relay.
Okay.
That's right.
Uh, and this is a, and this is a use
case for Nostra that just, you know,
to me is, it's like, it's, it's
not even, yeah, it's, it's not.
It's Nostra protocol,
but because a lot of this stuff
doesn't even leave their relay.
It, it could be anything.
I mean, they could just roll their own.
I mean, it doesn't really,
that point doesn't really matter if
it's Nostra or if it's anything.
Exactly.
I'm just saying, you know,
there's been this question about,
so what do we do with the metadata?
And it seems like they've implemented
a solution that, that works.
I don't know exactly how it works,
but it's working and it's all open.
Um, but I, I think for me, the big
takeaway, because I've, I've been a,
I am a sovereign feeds user and my
sovereign feeds workflow is, uh,
it's a lot of steps and it's prone to
some errors because I, I use
external chapter marking technology,
external transcripts.
So that was quite nice
to just upload a file.
It gave me, of course, with some, uh, AI
gave me a description, very long one.
So I just copied the beginning.
That wasn't too bad.
That description, it did the chapters
very, uh, overzealous on the chapters,
you know, it gave me like 50 chapter
markers, which wasn't necessary.
I didn't feel like going in and editing the
ones out that were, that were too much.
And there's no images, although I
think they're going to do images.
Uh, and it just kind of worked.
It was very fast.
But again, for me, seeing my
payment data with the other stats,
that's really the big, that's the big aha.
It's like, ah, okay.
I've got everything here
except whatever Dave paid me.
Maybe I got rejected.
Maybe my money's not, your
money's no good here.
And, um, let me see him stripe me.
I look, I'm not going to stripe.
Um, oh yeah.
Maybe they just pass it on through and
maybe you don't even see it on the.
And from what I understand,
they're going to do,
they're going to do a lit and give you
a stream to go live.
Really?
Yeah.
No way.
Way.
Cool.
I mean, based on your, uh, VC activity,
it sounds like my live stream.
Yeah.
Oh, vibe coding.
You're vibe coding it too.
Yeah.
It sounds like, um, it sounds like live
stream bandwidth wise is not too bad.
It really isn't.
Okay.
And, and even, um, I'm running
right now, I'm running,
I think 12 live streams
with no one listening.
Um, but it, it takes up, uh, takes up
about a hundred, a hundred megabytes,
a little under a hundred
megabytes of memory per stream.
Cause it likes to keep it in memory.
A hundred megabytes per stream.
I think so.
Well, yeah, but it, but it's
reserving for lots of listeners.
So I could set it much lower.
I just wanted to know what it would be
if, if we had potentially, you know,
a hundred listeners per
stream, which is a lot.
I got you.
Okay.
Well, I mean, if that's, if that's the case
that, you know, I mean, you would think
that if host, if, if this
is, if this is that, I mean,
podcast hosts are talking
about doing video.
I mean, Lord, the bandwidth on video,
I got your $10 by the way, it's just,
it's showing up, it's showing up in
Stripe, but it's not showing up in the,
for some reason, maybe it shouldn't.
I thought it would show up in the, in the
fountain dashboard, but I don't see it.
Maybe I'm not looking in the right place.
Well, you can send me my merch whenever
you get around to it, my wine, my,
my wine glass with the
name, my name on it.
Yeah.
But I mean, like if podcast
hosts are talking about
doing video now and that's outrageously
bandwidth intensive.
Well, the big talk is about HLS.
Will HLS make it that much
less bandwidth intensive?
You know, I guess we could
talk about this for a minute.
Yeah.
HL.
Let's talk about this.
HLS, well, I guess first
off the alternate enclosure
for HLS streams is the right,
it is the right way to go.
I mean, cause you could,
you know, you could,
you could put an HLS
stream in the enclosure
tag, but in the, just straight
into the enclosure tag,
then an HLS can be audio
and video, either one.
I mean, it doesn't have to be either or
a HLS doesn't dictate what, what codec.
You use, it's just a delivery method.
So alternate enclosure really
is the right place to put that.
You could stick it in the
enclosure tag, but you know,
if you're going to take advantage
of, if you're going to take
advantage of HLS, the out breaking,
this is actually a big topic.
Let me, let me figure out that we actually
need to start at a different place.
Current problem with HLS from
an implementation standpoint
on the client side is that the built
in audio and video tags within
HTML five does not support it.
So you cannot hand, you
can't just hand off,
you can't roll an HTML
audio or video embed tag
and just hand off this HLS playlist
URL to one of those and have it work.
It won't.
Um, the, and it may in the future, but
that's, it's not reality right now.
So the HLS, okay, structurally speaking,
HLS is this, you take a piece of content,
a media file, audio,
video, doesn't matter.
You transcode it into multiple
different bit rates if you want to,
and then you chop up each of those files.
So let's say you have, let's say you have
a 4k video file that's, uh, five gigs.
You, you're going to offer it with
what they call adaptive bit rate.
So you're going to have
the ability to go from
4k all the way down to
640 by 480 and maybe
three options in between.
You're going to have a total
of five different files.
So that one five gig 4k
video file immediately
gets transcoded into
five alternate bit rates
and stored, and they all get stored in
some object storage backed, backing a CDN.
Then the, the, and those
files are stored in chunks.
So that you're, you're sending a,
a chunk at a time to the client.
So, so the, the good news
is you're not always
sending two gigs of
video data down the pipe
for someone to then load
up their device and play.
Right.
It does not have to,
and currently if you just drop an
MP4 video into a podcast feed, every
single client is going to download
the entire video first, then play it.
So you're, you're, you're, you know,
HLS from that standpoint may
save you bandwidth because
you're not paying for
bandwidth for people who
don't intend to consume the entire video.
And it's a better startup
experience because it
starts immediately and it's a better seek
experience because if they don't
cache it locally on device,
they can just go directly to the
chunk that they need.
And when you have the adaptive bit
rate, it can bounce chunk by chunk.
It can bounce between
the different bit rates
to get the one that's most appropriate for
your available bandwidth.
Now HLS works for audio
too though, doesn't it?
Yes, it does.
It does.
It's not, it does not dictate a, a codec.
You can use it for any codec you want.
And the way that it does that with them,
um, the way that it does that with the,
uh, adaptive bit rates is you have
sort of like a master playlist
that references other
playlists for the other,
for the different video files.
But again, you're going
to run, there's, there's,
there's really two drawbacks to HLS.
I'm not, I'm not being anti HLS.
I'm fine with, I think it's a great
idea in podcast clients, but I'm,
I'm just saying where
we're at currently, there's
going to be two challenges here.
Uh, the first one being
lack of built-in support
in the audio and video tags that
many, many people rely upon.
Right.
In HTML five, you can, you,
you would have to roll your own
plate like a JavaScript media
player or, uh, take one like an
open source one off the shelf.
Um, you know, and re and, and,
and use that you, you can do it.
It's just more, it's more work
and it's more JavaScript jobs.
Well, I'm going to tell you
now that I wouldn't put
too much work into it because I
don't think it's going to last.
People are going to go back to an audio.
I'm seeing it already.
It's like, yeah, it doesn't pay off.
I, I, when people say video, I'll just, I
don't want to sound like Rob and Todd, but
when people say video, they
really just mean YouTube.
That's it.
They mean YouTube and YouTube has
stats and monetization and all that.
And then they'll do it
for a couple months.
I'm like, well, that's lame.
I, I, I just don't see it.
I don't see it having the
future that everyone thinks.
When I hear about the
podcast, London show,
when I listened to the
power and also a new
media show, it's like the same hype
for, what was that Mark Cuban thing?
Fireside.
You know, and then spaces.
It's all, it's all the
future of podcasting.
No, it's not.
It's not.
It's, it's, you're going to have, you're
going to have a massive increase,
increase in bandwidth costs
and you're going to have to
store way more and process way more data.
Oh yeah.
Now this, this leads to, and that's.
It leads to tears, people
is what it leads to.
Buckets of tears, buckets
and buckets of tears.
And the real issue here is a podcast,
like band, band, yes, bandwidth is,
is problematic, but storage space
is also, it's a real issue.
Storage is, it's cheap, but it's not free.
No.
And if that five gig
video now becomes 12 gigs
because you have to transcode it into four
or five different formats.
Oh yeah.
I mean, you multiply that, you start
racking up some storage bills quick.
No kidding.
And the real issue, uh, backing this
is podcast, like podcast pollution.
It's just all over the place.
Podcast, pod pollution,
podcast pollution is real.
It's like that big garbage patch in
the middle of the ocean or whatever,
the plastic patch.
You mean Puerto Rico?
Puerto Rico, it's Puerto is,
it's the Puerto Rico problem.
Uh, it's, it's podcast Puerto Rico because
you have, so my, by my best guess,
80% of what's
in the podcast index is just junk, complete
junk, is total Puerto Rican pollution.
I think we should just
stay with pod pollution.
I don't think, I don't have a good vibe
about calling it Puerto Rican pollution.
Okay.
Pod, podcast pollution.
Yeah.
It's complete, it's, nobody will ever
listen to any of those episodes.
Never.
They just exist.
They will never be touched.
They will.
I, I did some re, I did some sort of
off the cuff research on this one time.
You mean, you mean a deep dive?
I did.
We're going to do a deep
dive on this today.
Deep dive, baby.
Yeah.
Deep dive.
Really?
Um, so I, I did some sort
of off the cuff stuff
maybe about a year and a half ago where
I was looking at, uh, about
90 days worth of logs.
It was the same podcasts
over and over again,
the same batch of podcasts
getting requested
and there was less than a million of them.
And the rest of the entire
four and a half million,
so like 3.6 million podcasts in the
index literally never get touched.
And so that's fine if
you're talking about,
if you're talking about
a few megs of audio.
So how many, how many are actually
being consumed according to your,
a little less, a little
less than a million.
And I mean, this is like
a year and a half ago
and somehow $7 billion comes out of that.
And I see none of it.
It's very interesting.
Um, it's fine if you, if you're,
if you're talking about,
it's fine if you're talking about
let's say 70 million episodes of, that
are only a few megabytes a piece,
but if you're
talking about set, you know,
70 million episodes that are five
gigs a piece, that's a problem.
That's a real problem.
Um, so, you know, that
I just, I don't know.
I, I, it's going to be
a hard push because the
real issue is that nobody
can compete with YouTube.
We're not with video.
They own all the infrastructure.
They, they have, they,
if you want to be a modern CDN and
push con and push video content.
No way you, to the, to the edge.
No, you can't do it.
YouTube has machines in every data
center everywhere in the world.
Yeah.
They cash it all locally.
They've partnered with
everybody to, you know, you,
when you're watching that YouTube video,
it's probably not coming from YouTube.
It's probably coming from
a data center within,
within a few hundred
miles of your location.
Yeah, exactly.
And podcast hosts can't, they,
they don't have that ability.
They have, YouTube has such
an infrastructure advantage
over everybody else that I don't see
them ever being able.
Nobody can compete.
No.
And we don't even know
if they're profitable.
Yeah.
They, they may lose money for all we know.
They've never told us if they don't.
Got to wonder.
Then we've got to wonder why they don't
spin it out as a separate company.
Well, you know, usually when things are,
usually when parts of your
business are, are really
profitable and doing well,
they usually tout that.
Yeah.
Spin it out.
But they sure don't, they
sure do not mention it.
No.
Just think of the, of the, of
the encoding and everything.
It's amazing what's going on over there.
Well, Alex sent me a thing of, you know, a
year or two ago saying, you know, showing
like all the custom, uh, what
do they call those things?
It's filled, uh, FPGs, filled, filled
programmable Gatorades, FPGAs,
all the custom FPGA chips
they have that, uh, that do
all their encoding form.
They have entire server farms of
custom encoding chips that they built.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Just for this.
You know, I see you see Brooklyn
one, one, two, but no, I mean,
you have to go back to first principles.
You can make a successful program with
a hundred listeners who support you.
A thousand is better,
but a hundred is okay.
You may be, you're not
making money at all.
I've been doing a podcast
for 17 and a half years.
No video, no frills, no bonus episodes,
no Patreon and two families
have lived off of it.
It's possible.
There's one thing, there's one caveat.
You got to have a good product.
That's it.
There are blogs making a million
dollars or $2 million a year.
Why?
He said, because they have good content.
People want to pay for it.
They want to support it.
It's no way you can have a million
great products in, in podcasting.
It just doesn't exist, but it could
be great for a hundred people.
So this, we got to get
out of this mindset.
We have to be big and the numbers,
leave that to Megyn Kelly
and Bill O'Reilly and Tucker
Carlson and leave that to Joe Rogan.
It's fine.
What are you really, what are
you really trying to achieve?
Do you want to be them?
Or do you just want to
have a great show and
have people supported
and enjoy it and have
a community, which is in
essence, what no agenda is.
It's just built up over time
and it doubled during COVID.
If you're not employing at least 50
people, you're hardly even a podcast.
But the whole industry,
everything is geared around that
thinking about charts and money
and downloads and all this stuff.
That's not what it's about.
It was never about, when we started,
it was never about money at all.
We weren't thinking of that.
I just want, I just
want to put out a show.
It was about the tech really.
Yeah.
It was just the fact that it worked.
You know?
Yeah.
This, this sort of leads to
a different topic though.
And this is.
Is it cooking related?
Not that I know of.
Okay.
Just checking.
It can be.
We can shift.
But there need, you know,
there really needs to be some standard
way of registering a pass through.
And this is relevant to what,
to what you're building as well
with your VC is there needs.
So, so let's, let's say as some, as I've
heard a couple of people say from now,
I think James
and Todd both said this, let's say that
HLS is, is a push and there's going to,
and it's, it's to some degree
successful on the hosting side.
Ideally from the hosts standpoint,
what the host wants, let's say,
let's say the hosting
company is Buzzsprout.
Buzzsprout is going to want is for the,
is for something like Apple
podcast or pocket cast
or whoever, they're going to want the
client, if at all possible to cons to,
to do one download and then serve that from
their own infrastructure to the client.
Ooh, that is, that is interesting.
Well, in that case, because I mean,
that would help them out greatly
for as bandwidth Costco,
but what that means is you're going to,
what the podcast industry
has always wanted, the
podcast hosting infrastructure people
have always wanted, they have wanted is,
well, you know, what
they call pass through.
They want, it was a huge
battle with Spotify.
Spotify initially was
caching all the episodes of
podcasts and the hosting
companies were like,
no, we, you know, you, you've
got, we need to track downloads.
So we want you to pass through
those downloads to us.
Yeah.
We want to see the con, we
want to see the get requests.
And so in this case,
there's such a bandwidth burden that
it would be really helpful if they
did not pass it through.
But in that case, you're
going to have to do something
to ping the podcast hosting company
and let them know that a download or a
stream or a view or a play did happen.
It's funny you bring
this up because in my,
in my sketches of what
I'm doing next, it was
literally, okay, so I download a
podcast, it goes onto a stream.
I want to signal, but I said,
maybe five people will listen
to this episode currently.
It might be 50 in a year.
I don't know.
It all, it's all relative, but I still
want that information to go back.
So what I had been VC-ing is just
doing a, actually re-downloading it.
So like, okay.
Just doing another get.
Yeah.
Just doing two, like, oh, two people
listen to it, do two more gets and then,
and then get rid of it.
Total waste of resources,
but I want them to have,
I want them to get the credit that,
that they, that they deserve
and that they need to have.
Although there's all kinds
of issue there because
it's coming from the same IP address.
So does it get parsed out?
So you're absolutely right.
If I could just send the stats
back, hey, two people listen to it.
Oh, by the way, two people listen to
it, this much of it from here to here.
That'd be great to send back.
And I, and I could, guess I could send it
back in some refer, as the user agent.
Hello, stats bot talking.
Yeah, we, we, we need to do,
we need a standardized way to do
this because it's going to, it's
going to help our immediate use case
and it would solve this problem for,
for getting passed through
without having it to,
without actually having to
serve this duplicate bandwidth
because spot, like Spotify
wanted to cache the content.
Yeah.
And, um, that would have actually been,
it would actually be good if these,
if you let
people cache the content, if you could
turn around and then tell them, um,
this is how many people did X.
This is the, yeah, this,
the, here's the stats.
Well, isn't this kind of what,
what Spurlock is talking about?
Part of it, part of it.
I thought, I thought Spurlock was
talking about reporting follower counts.
Is that not right?
Well, whatever.
I mean, follower counts or, or listen,
listen behavior, you know, anonymized.
No one has to know who it is.
It's irrelevant.
Now, of course you get an app like Franco.
He's not going to be able to do this
because he has a standalone app.
And I don't think there's any other way to
do it, but to have some infrastructure.
And a lot of, and a lot of apps
are, you know, or, you know,
quite a few apps are going to be that way.
They're not going to have backend
infrastructure that they can actually serve,
but the apps
that are big enough who drive tons of
bandwidth usage, they could do this.
Hey, podcast index could do it.
Come on, get some more disk space, Dave.
Gosh, the, which, you know, which leads
to yet another thing, which is the,
which is HTTP signatures, which I
think could come in to play with this.
What is the HTTP signatures?
HTTP signatures is, is
what, I don't know if this,
I don't know if they were
the first ones to use this.
I don't know the history of HTTP
signatures, but it was used by Mastodon.
Mastodon started using it to
verify that, to verify that a,
that the requests coming from
another instance were actually
coming from that other instance.
Right.
So you would, you, you sign your get
requests or your post requests or whatever,
you sign it with a public key.
You're basically designer,
not designing Noster now.
Not really.
I mean, it's, well, they, they,
they, they store content on relays.
They have keys.
Yeah.
But the, the keys identify people, not
the instance, you know, and it's, it's,
it's, I
mean, you're signing your message, but
I mean, lots of things, sign messages.
Um, the, so you have a, you know,
you would have a known public key.
Let's, let's say that, uh,
let's say that Apple is wanting to report
stats for a pass through of an HLS stream.
They could report that back to Buzzsprout,
but Buzzsprout could require, or,
or whatever the spec is that we're talking
about, could require them to sign it,
to sign the, the pad,
to the, the pass through ping.
So that they, so that Buzzsprout could,
could confirm that that actually
was Apple reporting it.
That way you, you get
rid of the fraud part.
Um, so that, that's, so
HTTP signatures, um,
Cloudflare had an announcement a couple of
weeks ago saying that they
were going to start, uh,
using HTTP signatures,
requiring, requiring
HTTP, HTTP signatures for bot traffic.
Oh, so if you're a bot,
they're going to want you to sign
your HTTP requests with a signature
basically to verify who you are.
And that's good because then
what that means is they can,
they can then build what, what
they were saying in this blog post.
It's a good blog post if, um,
try to look it up in a second.
What they were saying
is what they've always
taken the approach of
is trying to identify
bad bots through behavior.
They could switch gears and identify
good bots by the presence of an HTTP,
of a valid HTTP, HTTP signature.
Then they can say, okay, if you don't
sign your bot, your, your bot traffic,
we're going to treat you as
suspicious because you're not,
you're choosing not to
give us an, uh, some
sort of identifier of
who you actually are.
And that in and of itself will,
will be a sign of suspicion.
You know, the internet
is just so broken, Dave.
Oh, it is.
All the hoops we have to jump through
just to make something very simple,
viable and workable is kind of crazy.
Oh, it's, it's a, it's a complete mess.
It's a complete mess.
But you know, no, well,
Ben Rose, it's not,
it's not that all
hobbyists are suspicious.
It's because you, as a hobbyist, you
could sign your HTTP request too.
I mean, you just need to sign
it to say, okay, here's the,
here's what I am and what I'm doing.
I mean, I don't like it.
That's not what I'm saying.
I don't like having to do all this stuff,
but I'm just saying it makes some sense.
Um, because that's why Mastodon did it.
Mastodon was like, okay, try, here's the
thing is we run, you know, we run a,
um, the activity pub to
podcast index API bridge, man,
somebody shares a post and
mentions the bridge in there.
It gets a destroyed for
10, for 10 minutes.
Cause everything's just coming at you.
Yeah.
Every instance where somebody
follows anything on the bridge,
like they all start pinging it to death.
It's just, I mean, you,
you should see the logs.
It's just like, just rolling with,
and it goes on for 10 minutes.
Yeah.
You get, you get annihilated.
And if you can protect yourself by saying,
okay, I'm not, I'm going, you're like,
if you
can protect yourself by saying, okay, I'm
only going to accept traffic from you.
If you identify yourself as somebody that
I can then like validate as an actual,
you know,
as an actual other like organism that
I, that I want to interact with some,
you know, then that's,
that's an advantage.
I mean, you have to, you sort of to
live on the internet these days,
you have to accept
the fact that you can become a target
for destruction at any moment.
And you have to sort of like
take a defensive posture.
That's part of the breakage
you're talking about.
You know, you know, it
didn't used to be that way.
You people would get slash dotted or
whatever, but that was like an accident.
You know, these days that was actually
legitimate human beings clicking on things.
Yeah.
These days you get, you get
essentially get, you know,
slash dotted 10 X by LLM scrapers
like Anthropic and, you know,
and then they just hammered the
dog out of you without even
looking at your robots.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
That's, that's the worst part.
No one uses that anymore either.
No, no.
They just think the, a lot of the
AI companies, they just ignore it.
They don't even look at it.
They're just going to
scrape your stuff, man.
And if, and, and if the, if you can say,
if, if open AI signs their bot traffic,
you can just say, oh, I'm
just not going to accept it.
Sorry.
I don't want you on my side
or I don't want you in my,
in my podcast or whatever it is.
Well, I'm now I'm kind of down, man.
Talk me back up.
I can't, I can't believe all this
negativity you're telling me about.
I don't want it to be, it
doesn't need to be negative.
Like I, I didn't mean it to
be a negative, like a downer.
I'm just like, I actually
meant it to be a good thing.
Like we can, because if we, if we design
a, I mean, this is what, this is what this
podcasting 2.0 community is good at.
Yeah, that's true.
Good at designing protocols
to help with these things.
And if we can, to me, the
HLS thing is already,
it's already supported
alternate enclosure.
It's done.
Do it.
Go just run with it.
The thing that's needed though, is the
pass through protocol, how to report that.
And maybe Spurlock's thing, I'm, I'm,
I'm ashamed of myself for
not having printed out
his, his proposal on Reddit yet,
but I need to go back and do that.
So maybe he solved some of this.
I'm on the, I'll, I'll get prepared
for that for the next board meeting.
Uh, some celebrations.
Uh, I mean, it's pretty cool that,
uh, pocket cast seems to be, uh,
moving down the, uh,
the namespace route, adding pod role, which,
uh, everyone was kind of talking about.
That's cool.
Pocket cast, no slouch.
Can you can add pod role entries
with, um, split kit, right?
Sovereign feeds.
I mean, sovereign feeds.
Yeah.
Can we add one?
Uh, yeah.
I got one I want to add.
Yeah.
Hold on a second.
I can do it right now.
Let me see.
Episode info.
No.
Show info.
Does it pull out the index?
Uh, hold on.
It has to be.
I think it has to be.
Yeah, it does.
Uh, show info.
Uh, pod role.
Okay.
Add.
What are we adding?
Uh, fall of civilizations.
Fall civilizations.
Fall of civilizations.
And fall of civilizations podcast.
Boom.
Added.
Talk about coolness.
Yeah, that's awesome.
I love it when it works like that.
That, that is an amazing podcast.
Okay.
We're currently in our pod role is new
media show pod news, weekly review,
no agenda show
phantom power business hour this week in
Bitcoin and fall of civilizations podcast.
We should start adding more stuff to this.
Anybody want something
else while I'm here?
Yeah.
Boardroom boardroom boardroom.
Anyone want anything else?
I love the index is so
awesome that, that feature.
You're alone that you can just type in the
name of a podcast and it just shows up.
I mean, that in, in, you know, not
in some Silicon Valley based app.
It's just cool.
Yeah.
It really is.
I love that.
And, uh, I love it even better
when everything updates.
Well, twist the knife, bro.
I thought you might want to just
tell everybody what happened.
So in case they were concerned
that they'd noticed it, you know,
just not trying to twist the knife.
I mean, it's a, it's amazing that it
actually only affected us really.
Oh, it only affected the Godcaster stuff.
Oh, really?
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Cause so, um, you know,
I thought there was another
postmortem I needed to do as well.
And I forgot what it was.
What else broke?
Things that broke this week.
TTBW.
I'm looking through my notes.
I don't have anything on here
about postmortem of stuff.
I guess there was a, uh, uh, um, did
they do the, uh, the big show from, uh,
Bitcoin live, uh, Bitcoin 2025?
Cause I, I was out of pocket,
so I didn't see any of it.
I see it too.
Cause I was in the, in the forest.
You barely had a cell connection.
I'm looking through my notes.
I don't, I could have sworn that I had
another, another problem that I had.
Oh, well, I can't, I'll,
maybe I'll find it, but, uh,
another problem that I
had, that I had fixed.
Um, yeah.
So what, like, yeah, I just,
I mean, I just, I don't know.
I mean, it's a simple,
pretty simple issue.
I had, if you don't want to
go into it, that's fine.
If you just want to say, shut up,
Curry, don't talk about these things.
No, it's fine.
Um, trying, it's a,
it's actually kind of a
bigger discussion and I'm
wondering where to start.
So the prop here's, there's two,
there's, there's two issues going on.
Most there's this idea of how fast
do you want to update a podcast?
Yes.
Yeah.
That's the priority that we have in the
setting of the, the admin API dashboard.
Yeah.
Well, and so, you know, you, no matter
how fast your stuff is or you're,
you're still, you're limited, you know,
exhibit, you're limited to how, I mean, you,
you can't get everything instantly.
So you have to make trade-offs
on how fast you get.
So if you have something that's, there's
very few shows that update rapidly,
like every hour or something,
that's not common.
No, there's, there's one, the Fox
news hour report or something.
That's the, that's the, and the Fox business
news, which is actually kind of cool.
There's very, yeah, very few, you know,
I'd say less than a hundred that do that.
Yeah.
And so that's fine.
You, you just sort of like make a special,
you make some special
case for that and you
put those in a list and you're like, okay,
if I see that there's
a feed that's updating
like all the time, then I'll just make it,
make sure that it's over here
and it gets checked more often.
Everything else falls into most,
everything else falls into
this sort of like gray zone
where you really want,
what you really want is for that
podcast episode to be found within,
let's say an hour after release.
Within it.
Yeah.
If it's, if it starts to be two, three,
four, five hours, that becomes a problem.
Just ask Megyn Kelly.
Exactly.
Yeah.
She was flipping out.
It's always funny to hear
people flip out when
they have no idea what
they're talking about.
And no one will answer me at Apple.
What kind of company are you running?
You take our money for iPhones.
You don't even care about my show.
Yeah.
And like, like, uh, what
was it a couple of years
ago when Glenn Beck supposedly got banned
and he was like, oh, you
know, I'm freaking out.
Like they banned us.
I'm like, oh, they didn't ban you.
Just an update.
Yeah.
Um, but so you'd, you know, when it
starts to get a lot of hours, you think,
eh, now you, now you got a,
it's, you got a problem.
Yeah.
So you really want to hit that sort of
sweet spot between, you know, like,
like less than an hour,
hopefully less than that.
But you don't have to
like kill yourself to
get every update to be within 10 seconds.
Well, this is why we invented PodPing.
Yes.
Yes, exactly.
And there's so many shows
that update with PodPing
that this is mostly not a problem.
There's only a few hosts
that this is a problem for.
Even if, even if Apple, if Apple
would just think about, you know,
think about what they
would save in, we've been
through this before, of course,
but think about how much they would
save in bandwidth and cycles.
If they just monitored PodPing and updated
their database based upon PodPing,
they'd have hundreds
of thousands of shows.
They don't have to poll.
Exactly.
And it's, and you can
do a hybrid approach.
You just keep on polling
for the shows that
don't need it and use PodPing
for the ones that do.
And if Apple does it, yeah.
If Apple does it, everyone
will start using it.
It's so, it's, uh...
I guarantee you our bill
is smaller than Apple's.
Oh, I, no doubt.
No doubt.
But, so, but that there,
so that's one issue.
It's like how long after the show
comes out do you want to find it?
But then there's an,
there's sort of this intermediary issue
that is a little hard to count for.
And that is, that's the, the issue
we found ourself in with Godcaster.
And that is, so if you have
a show like, let's say,
like No Agenda or this
show, does it matter
if the show comes out?
Does it matter if this episode pops up
in your podcast player at 3.30 or 4.15?
I can tell.
Probably not.
I can tell you from
personal experience, yes.
It matters a lot to people.
To a vocal minority.
I wouldn't, the reason why I wouldn't
say it's a vocal minority, it's vocal,
but I don't know if it's a minority, is
because we're on a very set schedule.
Okay, you, you have 850,000 uniques.
How, when it doesn't show up,
when it doesn't show up in Apple
Podcasts for an hour, how many
of those people do you hear from?
My whole Twitter timeline is full.
How, how many do people
is that representing?
After, after one hour, I'd say 50, if it's,
if it's more than that, it's hundreds.
And the emails, hundreds.
Hundreds out of 850,000,
though, is what I'm saying.
Yeah, but that's the people who,
who, who were annoyed by it.
How many people, here's what,
okay, again, I'm just being,
from my perspective, because
I'm on a schedule, people
know when to expect it.
It comes out at the same time,
we post it on the website,
so they see it come up on the
website, that's, that's another problem.
Well, it posted here, you posted
it, you posted about it on Twitter,
it's not on my podcast app.
This is where the problem starts.
So they, so they, so they see it,
they see a ping, okay, it's coming,
and it doesn't come.
My fear is that if someone
doesn't get it for four hours,
which has happened on Apple, it
happens on other platforms,
my fear is they're going to,
they might listen to something else.
And I think it's a valid fear.
Sure.
And that's why I'm, I'm
excluding the four hour thing.
I'm saying only sub one hour things.
Let's, it's, if, if on, if on Sunday
you release no agenda and if,
if on Sunday you release
no agenda and it gets to most
podcast apps within 15 minutes.
That's fine.
And on Thursday it gets to most
podcast apps within 40 minutes.
What I'm saying is 99% of your audience
is not going to be bothered by that.
I'm just 30 minute difference.
I'm just going to push
back a little bit because
the problem is I signal
to them it's out and
people don't understand how this
works and they don't have to.
So they, they've seen, uh, some
art, uh, and that's, that's a big,
a big part of the audience
that, you know, I have a hundred
thousand people following me.
So let's say at least a thousand
are going to see it, maybe more.
They see the art, they
don't see it in their app.
There's a disassociation there
that, that people don't understand.
That's, and that's fine.
I understand.
And, and Daniel's making, uh, uh,
Daniel's making a good, you know,
he's making the same
point in the boardroom
is, is the promotion,
the promotion versus
episode drop mismatch.
And, and I, yes, and I'm cool with that.
And that's, but everyone does that.
And the, and the, what I mainly hear
from people is not Apple sucks is no,
you forgot to upload to Apple.
Right.
That's what I get.
But so that's the difference
between where podcasting started.
We didn't have any of these
social media networks.
You would just, it was
actually delightful.
Oh, something new came in.
So there is a, there is a,
there's been a change over time.
Thank you, Daniel.
That yes, it's the promotion part.
You're like, Hey, new episode.
It's out, come and get it.
Uh, and it's not, it's
not in their devices.
And, and the first
person they blame is me.
They don't really blame Apple.
That's why Megan Kelly went off
because people were blaming her.
She's getting emails and
you didn't upload it.
And you're no good because
people just don't understand.
And you can't, it's, I don't think
we need to expect that from them,
but I don't want to belabor it.
I'm just telling you there's,
there's real pain there.
Right.
Yeah.
And maybe that's why I use pod ping.
That's why I use pod ping.
I'm not crazy.
Your show is probably a, maybe
your show is not a great example.
I would consider myself a more,
a more normal podcast listener.
And what I mean by normal is I don't,
I don't keep track to the
minute of when a show is
supposed to be released.
I kind of roughly know
what day they come out on
can probably count on
one hand of the number
of times that I've like
gone into my app and tried
to refresh to see if a show that I know
is going to drop that day is there.
I just, I just have a more casual
relationship with my podcast,
which I think represents
a majority of people.
That's what I'm disagreeing with.
We have, it's a majority.
No, we have a very small audience
with Curry and the Keeper.
If we even record an hour
later, we already have emails.
Are you okay?
What's going on?
Casey said, or CK said, you
know, Curry and the Keeper said,
which is separation anxiety disorder.
They're already, people are texting Tina.
When's it coming out?
You know, so it's, it's
an expectation that is,
maybe it's a certain kind of podcast.
Maybe that's a, maybe that's a
better way of explaining it.
So for instance, people have no idea when
Rogan's podcasts are going to come out.
They have no idea.
Right.
There's no schedule there.
It's like, yeah, we'll do it
Monday, Tuesday, then Thursday,
maybe nothing until Monday.
Because there's no set schedule.
When you set a schedule,
which is my golden rule,
try to release the same
day, the same hour.
Do you set that expectation?
And then when it fails, people freak out.
That's okay.
That, I think you're, I think, I
think you're explaining it too, is,
is the hardcore schedule.
That's it.
When, if you take a show, take a
show like pod news, weekly review,
that show comes out just, you
don't know when it's, you know,
it's going to come out
sometime Friday morning,
but, but there's no exact
time that it comes out.
So you're just, you just, you just know to
expect at some, at some point on a Friday
morning, uh, U S time.
Well, well, well, if I don't, if I wake
up Friday morning and it's not there,
I'm bummed because that's my dishwasher
emptying and stacking podcast.
Right.
I know.
But did you, do you know if
it came out at 3am or 5am?
No, I don't.
And, but that's because,
that's the point I'm making,
but they're releasing at a smart time.
I get it.
But the, um, the, this is all groundwork
for what I'm trying to explain here.
And I just keep grinding you to a halt.
I know I'll be quiet.
I'm just disagreeing.
Sorry.
I don't want to, I don't
want to stop the train.
No, it's, it's, you're
making a valid point about,
about podcasts that are on a definitive
ultra tight schedule.
What I'm saying is, um, a show like power,
if it comes out at 3am our time or 4am our
time really doesn't make a
whole lot of difference.
Yeah.
I'm going to say one more
thing and I'll shut up.
I'm triggering you so hard right now.
Because this has been my life
for almost 18 years, uh,
people who are in Europe, they expect
that with their breakfast, they
expect it at, you know, at,
at 7am it's going to drop and
it doesn't, their day may be ruined.
So the time schedule for us is great,
but not necessarily for someone
in a different time zone.
I'm just saying that the
behavior of people is
when a podcast comes out on the same day
at more or less the same time,
they schedule their lives and their
activity and their joy around it.
Sure.
And so the two variables that don't
fit in what you're trying to,
and then I'm really going
to stop the two variables that
don't, I'm going to try it.
No, probably not the two,
because I live this.
I really, this, this is people say, what's
your number one rule of podcasting?
This is it release on the
same day at the same time,
because people build
their lives around it.
And when they don't get it,
they're going to go find something
else because it's like crack.
I need my thing.
I need my fix.
And well, what else is
in my podcast app that
and promotion when
promotion is asynchronous
to the update that every single no agenda,
I tell people get a modern
podcast app because
you want it tied into podcast index,
because it understands pod ping.
And within 90 seconds of me releasing
the show, it's going to be in your app.
That's the number one
selling point that I tell
everybody about the modern podcast apps.
Okay.
You, you are a, you are
a successful podcaster.
Exactly.
This, you're like an LLM right now.
I'm just going to prompt you and you're
going to say, let's take a deep dive.
What, what you are a
subscriber to on the media.
Okay.
This is a good podcast called
on the media, correct?
This is a good example.
Yes.
Okay.
What, you know, what days it comes out.
It comes out on Wednesdays,
the midweek show.
What time does it come out?
Okay.
What hour of the day does it release?
In my schedule, that show doesn't matter
as much because it will always be there
when I walk Phoebe Wednesday night.
So I'm.
And that's exact, that's
the point I'm making.
But that, but if my schedule to listen
to it was earlier in the day, it,
I might feel differently about it.
So it's, it varies per podcast.
It varies.
In an ideal world, in an
ideal human behavior world,
every podcast would come out
the same time, the same day.
I think in the world we live in today,
not 15 years ago, then it was just crap.
I can't believe an episode came out.
Your, your original,
your original desire for podcasts was that
you'd go to bed that night and you'd wake
up in the morning and
you'd have new stuff.
But that was based on different criteria.
It was based on no bandwidth.
Yeah, but sure, sure.
I understand.
But that, but I'm, what I'm saying is
that, but the podcast, the, the desire,
the, the, the goal of podcasts was,
was to make the delivery
asynchronous to the publishing.
No.
The linear brought was to break
the linear broadcast model.
No, that's where you didn't, that,
no, that's, that's what it became.
The original intent behind
podcasting is we have no bandwidth.
There's no experience between
clicking and experience.
It would take three, five, 10 minutes
before something downloaded and played.
That was, that was, but that's different.
That that's different from,
so the last yard was what you
don't know won't hurt you,
but it doesn't mean that
I still didn't want
to get it approximately at the same time.
Anyway, we're going to go
round and round on this and,
and we're never going to come to
agreement, but I saw last night, Netflix,
for some reason, just broke
and nothing was working.
And I went on X and people were
losing their ever loving minds.
Right.
Because technology didn't work
the way they expected it to.
And people just come to expect things.
If you train them that
way, which is what I do.
And when technology lets me
down, it lets everybody down.
So, okay, let's, I think we're getting,
I think we're getting bogged down
in the weeds of, of shows that,
that are shows that have a very predictable
schedule, which many, many, many do not.
These are, these, so the, the show I
mentioned earlier, fall of civilizations.
Look at the feed on that thing.
There are months that go by
between episodes because
each episode is a very
intense research project.
And so there may be four
months between an episode.
Yeah.
So you don't, you really have no clue
when that thing is going to come out.
Of course.
I'm in total agreement.
It's like goats, guns, and gold.
You don't know when something's coming
out and I'm always looking, Hey,
new episode, no new episode.
And all of a sudden
he'll do four in a week.
So yeah, of course there
are podcasts like that.
Of course.
Rogan is another example.
Good example.
You just don't know.
You don't know.
No.
And so for, for those shows.
It doesn't matter.
It just doesn't, it doesn't
matter if it's an hour,
if it takes an hour to
get the new episode.
So.
Unless everybody, everybody on Twitter
is going, wow, this is a great episode.
Oh, this is an awesome guest.
But, but at that point, the
episode has already shown up.
Not, maybe not an apple.
Uh, okay.
Okay.
But, uh, what I'm, what I'm trying to get,
what if this whole thing
has been about is trying
to get at, we, for God, for
Godcaster, we, what, what our,
our clients are serving radio,
our clients are radio stations
primarily in the radio stations.
Most of the daily podcasts that they have
in their lineup, they release at midnight.
They release at night in the
middle of the night at U S time.
Yeah, absolutely.
It's the middle of night U S time.
So there, so we have a time window
that we had, that we, it's like,
if it hits 6 AM and we don't have the
new episodes yet, then that's a problem.
Yes.
I completely agree.
And in a, in a, in a, in a,
yes, that's absolutely the,
the biggest problem I have is I stream
live and I get it out live.
If we just recorded a podcast and
then we just release it, you know,
every Thursday at 8 PM, it will be fine.
And so that's in, that's
what the issue was that
caused this is that script broke because
I was trying to fix, I think there's
something wrong with red circles, pod pings.
Um, I'm just, they're not, they
don't seem to be acting right.
I'm not getting them in a predictable
way that I, I, they are coming through.
It seems like they just
don't seem accurate.
So I'm not sure what's going on there.
And so while I was trying to fix a
problem with, uh, with red circles,
pod pings, and they have a, have a
script that checks the Godcaster.
Uh, so there's about roughly
6,000 feeds in God, Godcaster.
It makes sure to check those,
uh, feeds about once an hour.
Yeah.
Um, to make sure that we're up to date.
And so that I was making
a change to that script
to account for the red circle because
it was excluding red circle from the
script because red circle does pod pings.
So I, I just, I removed
that exclusion so that
it would force check red circle as well.
And I made a couple of other changes
that I noticed need to be made.
And I had a typo in
there and it just broke.
And so all of a sudden
you had this huge delay.
Yeah.
That we don't know.
And it just brought this up,
this whole idea back of, well,
what is an acceptable delay?
You know, is it 10 minutes?
Is it five?
Is it, is it 30?
Is it one hour?
It's different.
I mean, it's different for all for each.
Different shows have different needs.
And for different people.
Totally agree.
I am going to dedicate
myself because of this very
conversation to promoting
pod ping everywhere
I go because we have fixed the problem.
It has been fixed.
And so it actually hurts me that you
and I are having this conversation,
although entertaining.
I'm sure it's good listening.
It hurts me because we have
such a beautiful fix that
hundreds of thousands
of podcasts are using.
But the biggest podcast clients, let's
just say Spotify and Apple, are just too,
I don't know, ignorant, not invented here.
I don't know what your problem is.
Get your shit together, people.
Fix yourself.
Seriously, fix yourself.
This is one thing we could do to
fix a huge problem in the industry.
Apple looked bad.
They just looked bad.
They looked like they
were lame and stupid.
And by not using pod ping and by not calling
your top shows and saying who are you
hosted with, all right, let's get them on.
It's so simple.
I could vibe code it for you.
It's that simple.
Please do that and send it to Ted.
I mean, I do it in Swift.
It's a solved problem.
And it's one of the biggest,
biggest innovations that we
have put into the podcasting
world that solves such a big problem.
It's just, it's baffling that
people are not all over this.
It's baffling.
Does Pocket Cast use it?
Pocket Cast use pod ping?
I think they do.
I bet you they do.
Because I talked to their
engineer and I think I gave him,
I think I sent him the
documentation on it.
I'm almost positive.
Yeah.
So that is just, it's just
painful because we fixed this.
We have fixed this problem.
When people say to me, you haven't uploaded
to Apple, get a better podcast app.
That's the answer.
Get a better podcast app.
So it hasn't updated on Pandora.
What are you doing?
You should be arrested for
using Pandora for your podcast.
That's illegal.
I didn't even know they had podcasts.
I didn't either, but apparently they do.
Yeah.
Pod ping comes standard with blockchain.
So it's got to be great.
Good point, Chad.
Oh, Apple's now using blockchain.
Yeah.
Nathan G posted a blog post.
Pocket Cast does support pod ping.
Of course they do.
Yeah.
And that's beautiful.
It's beautiful.
I need to take a, I need
to do a screenshot on my
phone one day of whenever
you release this show.
Yeah.
And it pod pings of all the apps
that notify me like immediately.
They notify you what?
That they have it?
Yeah.
There's a, there is always
like a cast, cast-o-matic.
It's like an act.
Because I usually have
an act that comes back.
Well, I'll get a push notification.
It's like new episode,
new episode, new episode.
You know, it would be cool to see
which, like, time it and say, okay,
I got these few, these handful of apps,
like, within, you know, five minutes.
You know, it's such an, it's such an
important part of the broadcast ecosystem.
I love the live pod, the lit pod ping.
It's the most awesome thing.
I always say, hey, get
a modern podcast app.
When we send out the bat signal,
i.e. we go live, you'll be notified.
Yeah.
It's like, it's so simple.
It's one of the, it's one of the most
beautiful things that we have in,
in podcasting today.
Infuriatingly simple.
Really?
Well, I'm sorry.
I hope, I hope you don't hold it against
me that I just went, went full boring,
you know, on, on this topic.
But I'm very passionate about it.
The most annoying part
was that you were right.
And that made me angry.
Wow.
I wish my wife would be like that.
You know, I'm angry because you're right.
I just wanted to blow past
you and get to my point.
And you just kept making good points.
And I was like, dang it.
Why can't you just be wrong?
Hey, I'm wrong plenty of times.
You get me all the time.
Yeah.
Shall we, shall we thank some people?
Oh yeah, sure.
Yeah, we've been rolling, haven't we?
Yeah.
Well, I want to make sure
you get out on time.
We have some boosts coming in live.
971 sats from Dave Jackson.
He says, I listen to you at Walmart
grocery shopping every Friday night.
That's how I party on Friday nights.
Party at the Walmart.
That's right.
School of podcasting.
One, one, two, three sats from Lyceum.
I miss you guys.
Here's a short part of
a Fibonacci sequence.
All the best.
Martin Lindeskog.
All right, Martin.
He sent that twice for some reason.
Coming in from, from.
Twice is better than once.
That's right.
One, two, three, four from Salty Crayon.
Hello, boardroom.
Gone are the days of using
the keep it simple sucker
method for V4V apps and the simplicity
of boosting anyone from
your favorite enabled app.
So we're back to the same camps.
Rent, run slash rent a node or
get forced into Fountain app,
which still cannot show live
video in the app itself.
$50 a month is unrealistic for new or
less than $10 a month earning podcasters.
That is in sats a month.
If they are lucky.
Sticking with Keyset.
Not everyone wants NOS or Bolt 11 either.
This is not motivating.
Whoa.
You know, I, I rage quit
the telegram group the
other day because there's so podcasting
to no, no, it's one of Stephen
B's, uh, Emporium of apps.
Okay.
There's just so much, you know, just
this infighting over, you know,
the price is too high and you're
not using Keysen and you know, the
Bitcoin forever and all this stuff.
And I just like this.
Okay, fine.
I just had to leave because it's
just, it just gets me all worked up.
The Bitcoin for Bitcoin forever, maybe, but
we only get two booster grams this week.
So I'm not real convinced that
Bitcoin forever is working here.
By the way, uh, allow me to play you
two short clips from Bitcoin 2025.
Lord.
Your vice president, JD Vance.
But I actually think that
where Bitcoin is going
is as a strategically important asset for
the United States over the next decade.
It's one of the reasons why
president Trump with the help of,
of our great AI guy, David Sachs.
It's one of the reasons why
we started the Bitcoin.
I want to be the great AI guy.
Because we want to start to
put in motion the strategic
importance of Bitcoin for the
United States government.
We know that the PRC doesn't like Bitcoin.
The People's Republic of
China doesn't like Bitcoin.
Well, we should be asking
ourselves, why is that?
Why is our biggest adversary
such an opponent of Bitcoin?
And if the communist Republic of
China is leaning away from Bitcoin,
then maybe the United States
ought to be leaning into Bitcoin.
And that's one of the things
that we're going to be doing.
Worst possible take.
Reasons to use Bitcoin.
China hates it.
Okay.
Why should you use Bitcoin?
Because of the communists.
The communists don't like it.
So it's good.
And here is a super cut of
all the rest of Bitcoin 2025.
Stable coins.
From stable coins.
Stable coins for Bitcoin.
Stable coins.
He goes on and on and on and on.
I like that one effeminate guy.
Stable coins.
We move on with a
thousand sats from Daoma.
D-A-O-M-A-H.
Is this?
I don't recognize this name.
Do you?
No.
Daoma?
Well, just in case.
Thank you for supporting us.
He says, Christ has ascended.
All right.
Amen, brother.
Amen to that.
333 from Salty Crayon.
Coming in from Curio Caster.
Adam, if you think Max Velocity
is nerdy, watch Ryan Hall, y'all.
This is it.
Why'd you boost it on podcasting 2.0?
He has way more going on
and has an AI bot called
Y'all Bot that does weather updates
and snaps back at the
chart for talking crap.
Okay, Cotton Gin, 1234, hello,
Franklin, he says, from the pre-stream.
Sage Single confirmed
from Salty Crayon, 111.
Dreb Scott, 7777,
pre-boosting the boost boost.
Hoping you got some much-needed time away.
Yes, it was very nice.
Thank you very much.
And I've hit the delimiter.
You're right.
We didn't get it.
Well, we weren't here, so it's not
expected to get a lot of sats.
That's true.
I forgot about that.
Oh, wait.
Last one comes in from Martin Lindeskog.
By the way, great opportunity to send us
a row of ducks, this being show 2-2-2.
He sends us 2-2-2-2.
Oh, yeah.
Fascinating discussion
about publishing time.
Adam, I understand your golden rule.
Dave, I like your take on the issue.
Now I have to create a new
podcast with a co-host,
create a listening behavior
according to the bat signal.
Maybe an afternoon tea time.
Go podcasting and podping.
Yes.
Oh, Martin, quit being a politician.
Pick a side.
Really?
Stop being a libertarian.
Who won?
Oh, I've got some PayPals.
I've got Buzzsprout.
$1,000.
Baller.
Shot caller.
20-inch blades.
Only Impala.
Ah, thank you, brother, so
much for keeping us rolling.
Thank you.
That's much appreciated.
The index hums along.
Thanks to you and everyone's
support of the show.
Every month.
Thank you, Tom and Kevin and
all the guys over there.
Appreciate it.
And the gals.
And the girls.
Let's see who we got.
We got Oystein Barra, $5.
Thank you, Oystein.
Yep.
Jorge Hernandez, $5.
This is a mix-up because I
didn't have time to print them.
Michael Goggin, $5.
Thank you, Michael.
James Sullivan, $10.
Cone Glotzbach, $5.
I think Cone is, I think
he's part of Antenapod.
Oh, well, I like Antenapod.
It's almost positive.
It's like the most open source podcast
ever in the universe or something.
Yeah, you can't get more open
source than that thing is.
Christopher Reamer, $10.
Jordan Dunville, $10.
Chris Bernardik, $5.
Dreb Scott, $15.
Thank you.
Michael Kimmerer, $5.33.
Pedro Goncalves, $5.
Who is this?
Oh, here's a new one.
Aaron Bergman, $5.
Thank you, Aaron.
And his message says, Godspeed.
He's been what?
His message said, Godspeed.
Godspeed to you, brother.
Oh, Martin.
Martin sent a 1776 and says,
Adam won, but I voted for Dave.
Okay.
Yeah, classic politician.
You're a libertarian is what you are.
Oh, $25 from the School of Podcasting.
That's going to be
Daniel and Dave Jackson.
Thank you.
Thank you, boys.
Oh, no.
School of Podcasting.
That's Dave Jackson.
Yeah, okay.
Future of Podcasting is D&D.
So this came from the
school or the future?
The school.
Oh, that's from Dave.
Yeah, okay.
Present, not the future.
His message says, nice to have you back.
Go podcasting.
Yes.
Thank you, Dave.
And we got some, we got some boost grams.
We got Chaos 99, 2000 sats.
Thank you.
It says, great episode, gents.
That came through Fountain.
Thank you.
Appreciate that.
And the delimiter.
CSB.
I see 14, 160 sats.
Thank you, brother.
Through Fountain, he says, howdy,
non-Slavic friends, Adam and Dave.
Today, I want to recommend my own podcast.
Just search for field recordings
by CSB in any app to enjoy pure,
unedited soundscapes.
No talking, no narration, no voices,
just birds singing fucking songs.
Just like tears in rain with
non-flying cars humming in background.
Other noises, some jarring, some nicer.
No talkie.
Press play, focus, and let
the world be your soundtrack.
Subscribe now, bro.
Your friendly neighborhood slov.
Yo, CSB.
Nice.
Now, that is not AI.
That is not LL.
No, no.
That's pure CSB.
Now, that is, what is it
called again, the podcast?
Field recordings.
CSB's field recordings.
Very nice.
Pod roll.
Field recordings.
Hold on, let me see.
Let me see.
Field recordings podcast by CSB.
It is podcast index number 705-3501.
Field recordings.
Well, there it is.
It's in the pod roll.
In the pipe and in the pod roll.
Done.
You've been pod rolled.
Also, the field recordings by CSB podcast
includes a field recording by yours truly.
Something you recorded?
Yeah.
Nice.
Way back in the episode.
I used to do, what do I call them?
I used to go out on the
street with two mics on
my lapel at night and
I'd record it and I'd
talk to people, homeless people mainly.
It was called a, what do we call those?
Not soundscape.
A sound seeing tour, I
think is what we called it.
Sound seeing tour.
I'd go out like a Marconi
square there in San
Francisco with all the homeless people and
just walk around and talk to them.
That it was a full on stereo.
It was, people really liked that.
Yeah.
To do something like that again.
That's pretty cool.
That's part of a Hello Fred feature.
I don't think so.
No, man.
We're all about the hot rock
and top 40 music, everybody.
Hey, Fred.
Episode 26 from December
7th of 2024 is the Sipsy
Fork Wilderness as
recorded by yours truly.
Nice.
Well, we are, you're
in the pod role, Dave.
Beautiful.
Thank you.
Thank you, everybody
for, that's everything.
They have monthlies or that's all the.
That's it.
The podcast index is a value
for value proposition.
Everything that comes in for this show
goes directly to the podcast index.
You are supporting the
machines, the tens of machines.
What are we up to?
Like 40?
We've got to have 40 machines
running on that thing.
Tens of machines.
Yeah.
I've counted them up a while back.
I don't remember.
I thought you had like 30
crawlers and all kinds of stuff.
Oh, no, no.
It's only 10 aggregators.
Oh, oh.
I think it's like 27
machines or something.
27 machines.
Dave's, Dave's home
office is like Star Trek.
It's got all these logs going
and looking at everything.
Tail minus F is Dave's life.
That's what it is.
You don't want to know how many servers
total I manage across all my domains.
Oh, oh.
I bet it's 100.
Oh, it's close to 200.
Wow.
How can one man do it?
There's only one man that can do it.
His name is the Podsage.
He is Dave Jones, everybody.
All right, brother.
Yeah.
What are you doing this weekend?
Hanging out?
You're not going back into the wilderness?
No, no, no, no.
I'm finishing up our closet renovation.
The master bedroom renovation
is almost complete.
Oh, oh, oh.
Oh, very nice.
We're hosting some people for dinner.
So what I'll do is I'll update
this in a couple hours or so,
whenever I feel like it.
And then we'll see.
Tell everybody to contact Dave Jones.
No, you update it now,
and then I'll make sure the index doesn't
get it for at least a couple hours.
There you go.
Have a great weekend, brother.
You too.
All right.
Boardroom, thank you so much.
We'll be back here next
Friday with more joy.
See you then.
You have been listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
It leads to tears, people,
is what it leads to.